DANIEL RIOS VELEZ

SOFTWAREENGINEER

CONTACT

3108204165

 \searrow

riosdaniel01@hotmail.com



Cra. 55b # 14B - 91, Rionegro, Antioquia



SKILLS

- Java
- TypeScript / JavaScript
- SQL
- AWS
- AZURE
- Maven
- Gradle
- Docker
- Kubernetes
- Splunk
- P00
- TDD
- Software Architectures
- Event Driven
- · Reactive programming
- Scrum
- Teamwork
- Problem-solving

•

EDUCATION

System Engineer

Universidad Católica De Oriente

12/2017



LANGUAGES

English

Spanish





PROFILE

More than 10 years of experience in software, analysis, and implementation specifically in Backend and supporting new designs. Guided under agile methodologies and architectures such as SCRUM, DDD, SOA, Event-Driven, Microservices, Monolithics, Clean architectures, TDD, DDD,etc. Supported by technologies such as Java Versions, JS, Spring framework, Angular, cloud platforms such as AWS, Azure, SQL, among others described in myresume. Experience in projects with architecture patterns, integration patterns, Design, Functional and Imperative Programming, Clean Code, and CI CD.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 12/2021 to Current

EPAM | Project: Schlumberger

- Define and implement new designs to support integrations with other platforms using event-driven architectures that support message brokers.
- Coded, tested, and developed solutions in alignment with project requirements.
 Maintain microservices architecture with NodeJS, Python, Java 8, 11, Docker,
 Unit and Integration Tests, Spring, Jenkins, Postgress, MongoDB, Azure, and
 GCP.
- Define and implement microservices from scratch using clean architectures.
- · Analyzed solutions and coding fixes for software problems.
- Conducted full lifecycle software development from planning to deployment and maintenance.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 12/2020 to 12/2021

TEAM INTERNATIONAL | Projects: Bullhorn | Fastspring

- Define and maintain Microservices architecture with Java 8, 11, Docker, UnitTest, Spring, Jenkins, Postgress, MongoDB, AWS. Supporting integrations with other platforms using event-driven architecture.
- Implementation of unit tests and integration tests, guaranteeing quality in development.
- Meeting with the software development team to discuss project definitions and goals.
- Analyzing system and user requirements for the software product.
- Designing system integrations and project workflows.
- Writing clean, scalable Java code.
- Technical interviewer for backend projects with java and angular.
- Mentorship to Jr and Mid developers to increase the seniority level.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 11/2019 to 12/2020

S4N | Projects: Starbucks | Qiip

- Conducting software analysis, programming, testing, and debugging.
- Developed web applications using a variety of engineering languages.
- Conducted full lifecycle software development from planning to deployment and maintenance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

- Define and maintain Microservices using Java, CI CD, AWS, SQL, supported in Event-Driven, CQRS, DDD.
- Create new modules and integrate with other Microservices using Http Rest and Event-driven.



- Development pure functional programming with (VAVR, Library inspired in Scala) and Scala
- Interaction with AWS services, SNS, SQS, GIT, Trunk based, Splunk, Datadog, Swagger, Play Framework, Jenkins, Concourse, Docker, Kubernetes, Cassandra, Postoress. Kafka.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 01/2019 to 09/2019

TALOS DIGITAL | Projects: Graco | Pacifika | Soriana | Corona

- Delivered code to meet functional or technical specifications.
- Participated in code review meetings, providing input on bugs, inefficiencies and potential solutions to emergent issues.
- Modified existing software systems to enhance performance and add new features
- Interacted with clients to provide timely and relevant status updates.
- Hybris extensibility supporting the new functionalities required by the client implementing good development practices supported by design patterns such as decorator, strategy, builder and definition of extensibility of beans with spring.



• Development of functionalities with technologies such as java 8, javaScript, Sql spring framework, Solr, Apache tomcat.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 05/2018 to 12/2018

CEIBA | Project: Sura (TED)

- Coordinated installation of software systems and collaborated with user experience team on design and implementation of new features.
- Leveraged Agile methodologies to move development lifecycle rapidly through initial prototyping to enterprise-quality testing and final implementation.
- Implemented Scrum-based Agile software development for analyzing, designing and developing applications.
- Managed both back-end and front-end aspects of development process.
- Completed code debugging and implemented fixes to resolve problems based on priority system.
- Development and maintainability of microservices related to the health area, supported by meetings with the client, definition of requirements, design and implementation up to production.



- Implementation of requirements supported by technologies such as spring boot, java 8, sql database, layered architectures, unit and integration tests, CI CD supported by jenkins.
- Development of functionalities under the DDD methodology.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | 09/2012 to 04/2018

QUIPUX | Project: Traffic and Transport

- Reviewed project requirements to identify customer expectations and resources needed to meet goals.
- Programmed applications and tools using object-oriented languages with goalsof code abstraction, stability and reuse.
- Implemented performance, quality and efficiency measures to achieve aggressive production goals.
- Coordinated testing and validation procedures through software development lifecycle.
- Performed troubleshooting of post-release software faults to support live service and installed software patch design.

